Lesson 28 Patients and doctors病人与医生
First listen and then answer the following question.
听录音,然后回答以下问题.
What are patients looking for when they visit the doctor?
病人看医生时,渴望得到什么?
This is a sceptical age,
这是一个怀疑一切的时代
forefathers: n.  祖先
but although our faith in many of the things in which our forefathers fervently believed has weakened,
可是虽然我们对关于许多事物的、我们祖先所笃信的观念已不太相信,
our confidence in the curative properties of the bottle of medicine
我们对瓶装药品疗效的信心
remains the same as theirs.
仍与祖辈一样坚定.
This modern faith in medicines is proved by the fact
有个事实证实了现代人对药物的信赖,
that the annual drug bill of the Health Services is mounting to astronomical figures.
就是卫生部门的年度药费上升到了天文数字,
and shows no signs at present of ceasing to rise.
并且目前尚无停止上升的迹象,
The majority of the patients
大多数病人
attending the medical out-patients departments of our hospitals feel
到医院门诊部看病时觉得
that they have not received adequate treatment unless they are able to carry home with them
如果不能带回一些药物回去,就没算得到充分的治疗
some tangible remedy in the shape of a bottle of medicine,
象一些看得见摸得着的东西如一瓶药水,
ointment: n.  药膏
a box of pills,or a small jar of ointment,
一盒药丸、一小瓶药膏等等.
and the doctor in charge of the department
负责门诊的医生
is only too ready to provide them with these requirements.
也非常乐意为前来看病的人提供他们想要得到的药物.
There is no quicker method of disposing of patients
没有比这样处理病人更快的方法了:
than by giving them what they are asking for,
病人要什么就给什么,
and since most medical men in the Health Services are overworked
因为卫生部门的大多数医生都超负荷工作,
and have little time for offering time-consuming
所以没有多少时间提出一些计费时aa
and little-appreciated advice on such subjects as diet,
而又不受人欢迎的忠告,如注意饮食、
right living,and the need for abandoning bad habits etc.,
生活有规律、需要克服坏习惯等等,
the bottle,the box, and the jar are almost always granted them.
结果就是把瓶药、盒药、罐药开给看病的人而完事大吉.
Nor is it only the ignorant and ill-educated person
并不只是那些无知和没受过良好教育的人
who has such faith in the bottle of medicine.
才迷信药瓶子.
It is recounted of Thomas Carlyle
据说托马斯.卡莱尔有过这么一件事:
that when he heard of the illness of his friend,Henry Taylor,
他听说朋友亨利.泰勒病了,
he went off immediately to visit him,
就立刻跑去看他,
carrying with him in his pocket what remained a bottle of medicine
衣袋里装着一瓶药,
prescribe: v.  开药方, indisposition: n.  小病
formerly prescribed for an indisposition of Mrs.Carlyle's.
那还是以前他妻子不舒服时吃剩下的东西.
Carlyle was entirely ignorant of what the bottle in his pocket contained,
卡莱尔不知道药瓶子里装的是什么药,
of the nature of the illness from which his friend was suffering,
不知道他的朋友得的是什么病,
and of what had previously been wrong with his wife,
也不知道他妻子以前得的是什么病,
but a medicine that had worked so well in one form of illness
只知道一种药对一种病有好处,
would surely be of equal benefit in another,
肯定对另一种病也会有好处.
and comforted by the thought of the help he was bringing to his friend,
想到能对朋友有所帮助,他感到欣慰,
he hastened to Henry Taylor's house.
于是急急忙忙来到了亨利.泰勒家里.
History does not relate whether his friend accepted his medical help,
他的朋友是否接受了他的药物治疗,历史没有记载,
but in all probability he did.
但很可能是接受了.
The great advantage of taking medicine is that it makes no demands on the taker
服药的最大优点是:它对服药人没有要求,
beyond that of putting up for a moment with a disgusting taste,
只需暂时忍受一下令人作呕的味道即可.
and that is what all patients demand of their doctors--
这也正是病人对医生的要求--
inconvenience: n.  不便
to be cured at no inconvenience to themselves.
病要治好,但不要太麻烦.